<xml>
    <brief>Retrieve data on a single attribute</brief>
    <issue-id>268</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Retrieve data on a single OKAPI geocache-attribute.</p>

        <p>OKAPI attributes are identified by an unique ID called an <b>A-code</b>.
        All OKAPI attributes are shared among all OKAPI servers. Once an attribute is
        published (e.g. via the <b>attribute_index</b> method), it won't
        disappear in any of the future OKAPI revisions, nor will its meaning change.
        Some attributes may get discontinued in the future, but they will remain accessible
        by their original A-code.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='acode'>
        The A-code of the attribute you're interested in.
    </req>
    <opt name='langpref' default='en'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of ISO 639-1 language codes. This indicates the
        order of preference in which language will be chosen for fields like
        <b>name</b> and <b>description</b>.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='fields' default='name'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of field names which you are interested with.
        See below for the list of available fields.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='forward_compatible' default='true'>
        By default, OKAPI will return an empty placeholder if you ask for an
        unknown attribute. If you'd like to catch such errors and handle them
        differently, then you may change this behavior by setting this parameter
        to <b>false</b>. Then, OKAPI will return HTTP 400 error response,
        instead of the placeholder (note that it behaves differently in the
        <b>attributes</b> method).
    </opt>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of fields you have selected in the <b>fields</b>
        parameter. Available fields:</p>

        <ul>
            <li>
                <p><b>acode</b> - string, the A-code. Unique identifier of the
                attribute.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>name</b> - plaintext string, name of the attribute (language is
                selected based on your <b>langpref</b> parameter),</p>

                <p>If you think your language is missing, then feel free to add missing
                translations directly to OKAPI repository. See
                <a href='https://code.google.com/p/opencaching-api/source/browse/trunk/okapi/services/attrs/attribute-definitions.xml'>here</a>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>names</b> - a dictionary of all known names of the attribute, in
                various languages (ISO 639-1 language code is used as dictionary
                key).</p>

                <p>If you think your language is missing, then feel free to add missing
                translations directly to OKAPI repository. See
                <a href='https://code.google.com/p/opencaching-api/source/browse/trunk/okapi/services/attrs/attribute-definitions.xml'>here</a>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>description</b> - HTML string, description of the attribute (language is
                selected based on your <b>langpref</b> parameter),

                <p>If you think your language is missing, then feel free to add missing
                translations directly to OKAPI repository. See
                <a href='https://code.google.com/p/opencaching-api/source/browse/trunk/okapi/services/attrs/attribute-definitions.xml'>here</a>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>descriptions</b> - a dictionary of all known descriptions of the
                attribute, in various languages (ISO 639-1 language code is used as
                dictionary key).</p>

                <p>If you think your language is missing, then feel free to add missing
                translations directly to OKAPI repository. See
                <a href='https://code.google.com/p/opencaching-api/source/browse/trunk/okapi/services/attrs/attribute-definitions.xml'>here</a>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>gc_equivs</b> - a list of Geocaching.com (Groundspeak)
                attributes, which have exactly the same (or a very similar) meaning. Each
                attribute is described as a dictionary of the following structure:</p>

                <ul>
                    <li><b>id</b> - ID of the Geocaching.com attribute,</li>
                    <li>
                        <b>inc</b> - integer, either 1 or 0. See Geocaching.com's
                        XSD for details on its meaning,
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>name</b> - the name of the attribute (as it is included
                        in Geocaching.com GPX files).
                    </li>
                </ul>

                <p>Note that one gc_equivs list may have multiple items on it, and
                that one Geocaching.com ID may be present in many gc_equivs.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>is_locally_used</b> - boolean, indicates if the attribute is <i>currently</i>
                used by <i>this</i> Opencaching server. Or, to be more specific, <b>true</b>
                means that the attribute can currently be included in the <b>attr_acodes</b> field
                of the <b>geocache</b> method in this OKAPI installation.</p>

                <p>Note that this flag can change in time. Some attributes may get
                introduced into other installations, whereas other attributes may
                (temporarily or permanently) stop being used. In general, we are aiming
                towards global unification of all attributes between all OC nodes,
                but this process will take time (and probably it will never
                be 100% complete).</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>local_icon_url</b> - an URL pointing to an image associated with
                this particular attribute in the local OC server, <b>or null</b> if the
                current server does not have any image for this attribute.</p>

                <p>Please note, that each OC server uses a different image set for their
                attributes. All these images come in various sizes and can change over time.
                In other words, if you want to use this attribute, then you must always be
                prepared to receive <b>null</b>, or an image of unexpected dimensions.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>is_discontinued</b> - boolean, indicates if the attribute is discontinued.
                This means that it is no longer in use at OC servers which run current OKAPI
                versions, i.e. geocaches are no longer tagged with this attribute. However,
                it may still be in use at servers which have not been updated yet to the
                current OKAPI version.</p>

                <p><b>Important:</b> This flag can change in time. Discontinued attributes can
                "come back to life" later. You can never be 100% sure you will not
                encounter them in OKAPI responses, so this field is purely informative.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </returns>
</xml>