<xml>
    <brief>Search for geocaches</brief>
    <issue-id>15</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Search for geocaches using some simple filters. All of them are
        optional, but you surely want to use at least some of them.</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                If you're looking for a way to keep your geocaching database in
                sync with ours, have a peek at the <b>replicate</b> module.
            </li>
            <li>
                Usually you will want to use search_and_retrieve method instead
                of this one. This way, you can get much more data in <b>one
                request</b>.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </desc>
    <opt name='type'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of cache type codes. If given, the results will be limited
        to the given cache types. For a list of cache type codes, see services/caches/geocache
        method.</p>

        <p><b>Notice:</b> If you want to include all cache types <b>except</b>
        the given ones, prepend your list with the "-" sign.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='status' default='Available'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of status codes. Only caches matching any of the given
        statuses will included in the response. For a list of cache status codes, see
        services/caches/geocache method.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='owner_uuid'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of user IDs. If given, the list of returned caches
        will be limited to those owned by the given users.</p>

        <p><b>Notice:</b> User ID and Username are two different things!</p>

        <p><b>Notice:</b> If you want to include all caches <b>except</b> the ones
        owned by the given users, prepend your list with the "-" sign.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='name'>
        <p>UTF-8 encoded string - the name (or part of the name) of the cache.</p>

        <p>Allowed wildcard characters:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>asterisk ("*") will match any string of characters,</li>
            <li>underscore ("_") will match any single character.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>Name matching is case-insensitive. Maximum length for the
        <b>name</b> parameter is 100 characters.</p>

        <p><b>Examples:</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>"name=the *" returns caches which name starts with "the " (or "The ", etc.),</li>
            <li>"name=water tower" returns caches which have <b>exactly</b> that name (case insensitive),</li>
            <li>"name=*water tower*" will match caches like "Beautiful Water Tower II",</li>
            <li>"name=*tower_" will match "Water Towers" but will <b>not</b> match "Water Tower".</li>
        </ul>

        <p><b>Notice:</b> Cache code and name are two different things - if you want to
        find a cache by its code, use the services/caches/geocache method.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='terrain' default='1-5'>
        <p>A string "X-Y", where X and Y are integers between 1 and 5, and X &lt;= Y.
        Only caches with terrain rating between these numbers (inclusive) will be returned.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='difficulty' default='1-5'>
        <p>A string "X-Y", where X and Y are integers between 1 and 5, and X &lt;= Y.
        Only caches with difficulty rating between these numbers (inclusive) will be returned.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='size' class='deprecated'>
        <p>Deprecated. Please use <b>size2</b> instead - this will allow you to
        differentiate "nano" vs. "micro" and "none" vs. "other" sizes
        (<a href='https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/155'>details</a>).</p>

        <p>A string "X-Y", where X and Y are integers between 1 and 5, and X &lt;= Y.
        Only caches with size attribute between these numbers (inclusive) will be returned
        (1 - micro, 5 - very big).</p>

        <p><b>Notice:</b> If you use this parameter, all caches which do not have a container
        (like Event or Virtual caches) will be excluded from the results. If you want caches
        with no container included, append "|X" suffix to the value of this parameter
        (e.g. "3-5|X").</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='size2'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of "size2 codes". Only matching caches will be
        included. The codes are: 'none', 'nano', 'micro', 'small', 'regular',
        'large', 'xlarge', 'other'.</p>

        <p><b>Note:</b> Not all OC servers use all of these. I.e. OCPL does not
        have 'nano' nor 'other' caches (but it might have them in the future).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='rating'>
        <p>A string "X-Y", where X and Y are integers between 1 and 5, and X &lt;= Y.
        Only caches with an overall rating between these numbers (inclusive) will be returned
        (1 - poor, 5 - excellent).</p>

        <p><b>Notice:</b> If you use this parameter, all caches with too few votes will be
        excluded from results. If you still want unrated caches included, append "|X" suffix
        to the value of this parameter (e.g. "3-5|X").</p>

        <p><b>Notice:</b> Some OC installations do not provide ratings for their geocaches.
        On such installation, this parameter will be ignored.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='min_rcmds'>
        <p>There are two possible value-types for this argument:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Integer N. If <i>N</i> given, the result will contain only
            those caches which have at least <i>N</i> recommendations.</li>

            <li>Integer N with a percent sign appended (e.g. "20%"). The result will contain
            only those caches which have at last <i>N%</i> ratio of recommendations/founds.
            Please note, that this is useful only with conjunction with <b>min_founds</b>
            parameter.</li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name='min_founds'>
        <p>Integer N. If <i>N</i> given, the result will contain only those caches which have
        been found at least <i>N</i> times. Useful if you want to skip "unverified" caches.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='max_founds'>
        <p>Integer N. If <i>N</i> given, the result will contain only those caches which have
        been found at most <i>N</i> times. Useful for FTF hunters.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='modified_since'>
        <p>A date and time string. This should be in ISO 8601 format (currently any
        format acceptable by PHP's <a href='http://php.net/manual/function.strtotime.php'>strtotime</a>
        function also will do, but most of them don't handle time zones properly,
        try to use ISO 8601!).</p>

        <p>If given, the list of returned geocaches will be limited to those which were
        created or modified since that date. (Note: currently caches do not get
        "modified" when user makes a log entry.)</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='found_status' default='either'>
        <p><b>Notice:</b> This parameter may be used only for requests signed
        with an Access Token (you will need to use <b>Level 3</b>
        Authentication).</p>

        <p>Should be one of the following:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>found_only</b> - only caches found by the user will be returned,</li>
            <li><b>notfound_only</b> - only caches <b>not</b> found by the user will be returned,</li>
            <li><b>either</b> - all caches will be returned.</li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name='found_by'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of user IDs. If given, the response will only include
        geocaches <b>found by at least one</b> of the given users.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='not_found_by'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of user IDs. If given, the response will only include
        geocaches <b>not found by any</b> of the given users.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='watched_only' default='false'>
        <p><b>Notice:</b> This parameter may be used only for requests signed
        with an Access Token (you will need to use <b>Level 3</b>
        Authentication).</p>

        <p>Boolean. If set to <b>true</b>, only caches which the user has marked as watched
        will be included in the result. This might be used to temporarily mark geocaches
        of particular interest (e.g. "all the caches I plan to find today").</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='exclude_ignored' default='false' class='deprecated'>
        <p>Deprecated (<a href="https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/349">why?</a>),
        please use <b>ignored_status</b> instead.</p>

        <p><b>Notice:</b> This parameter may be used only for requests signed
        with an Access Token (you will need to use <b>Level 3</b> Authentication).</p>
        <p>Boolean. If set to <b>true</b>, caches which the user has marked as ignored
        will not be included in the result.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='ignored_status' default='either'>
        <p><b>Notice:</b> This parameter may be used only for requests signed
        with an Access Token (you will need to use <b>Level 3</b>
        Authentication).</p>

        <p>Should be one of the following:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <b>ignored_only</b> - only caches which the user has marked as ignored
                will be returned,
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>notignored_only</b> - only caches which the user has <b>not</b> marked
                as ignored will be returned,
            </li>
            <li><b>either</b> - all caches will be returned.</li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name='exclude_my_own' default='false'>
        <p><b>Notice:</b> This parameter may be used only for requests signed
        with an Access Token (you will need to use <b>Level 3</b> Authentication).
        See <b>owner_uuid</b> parameter if you don't want to use OAuth.</p>

        <p>Boolean. If set to <b>true</b>, caches which the user is an owner of will
        not be included in the result.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='with_trackables_only' default='false'>
        Boolean. If set to <b>true</b>, only caches with at least one trackable
        will be included in the result.
    </opt>
    <opt name='ftf_hunter' default='false'>
        Boolean. If set to <b>true</b>, only caches which have not yet been
        found <b>by anyone</b> will be included.
    </opt>
    <opt name='powertrail_only' default='false'>
        <p>Boolean. If set to <b>true</b>, only caches which belong to at
        least one <b>active</b> Power Trail will be included.</p>

        <p>Power Trails are sets of geocaches. Only some Opencaching sites
        implement this feature. If this site does not implement it, and you
        will set this parameter to <b>true</b>, then you will <b>always</b>
        receive an empty result.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='powertrail_ids'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of Power Trail IDs. If given, then only
        the caches which belong to at least one of the referenced Power Trails
        will be included. Only <b>active</b> Power Trails are taken into
        consideration, IDs which reference inactive or nonexistent Power Trails
        will be ignored.</p>

        <p>Power Trails are sets of geocaches. Only some Opencaching sites
        implement this feature. If this site does not implement it, then
        whenever you use this parameter, you will <b>always</b> receive an
        empty result. Also, at the time of writing this, there is no method to
        retrieve any Power Trails, or their IDs. So, this parameter is
        primarily for internal use only.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='set_and'>
        <p>ID of a set previously created with the <b>search/save</b> method.
        If given, the results are
        <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logical_conjunction'>AND</a>ed
        together with this set.</p>

        <p>If you want to simply retrieve the contents of set, then please note
        the default value of the <b>status</b> parameter! You may want to
        override it in order to include unavailable and/or archived geocaches
        within the set.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='limit' default='100'>
        <p>Integer in range 1..500. Maximum number of cache codes returned.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='offset' default='0'>
        <p>An offset, the amount of items to skip at the beginning of the result. Combined with limit
        allows pagination of the result set. Please note, that the sum of offset and limit still cannot
        exceed 500. You MAY NOT use this method to list all the caches, it is for searching only.
        Have a peek at the <b>replicate</b> module if you need all the caches.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='order_by'>
        <p>Pipe separated list of fields to order the results by. Prefix the field name with
        a '-' sign to indicate a descending order.</p>

        <p>Currently, fields which you can order by include: <b>code</b>, <b>name</b>,
        <b>founds</b>, <b>rcmds</b>, <b>rcmds%</b> (tell us if you want more).</p>

        <p><b>Examples:</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>to order by cache name use "order_by=name" or "order_by=+name",</li>
            <li>to have the most recommended caches in front, use "order_by=-rcmds%",</li>
            <li>multicolumn sorting is also allowed, ex. "order_by=-founds|+name"</li>
        </ul>

        <p><b>Note:</b> For most other methods (like <b>bbox</b> and <b>nearest</b>),
        the default order is <i>by the distance from the center</i>. If you supply
        custom <b>order_by</b> parameter, then we will try to order by your preference
        first, and then by the distance later.</p>
    </opt>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of the following structure:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>results</b> - a list of cache codes,</li>
            <li>
                <b>more</b> - boolean, <b>true</b> means that there were more
                results for your query, but they were not returned because of the
                <b>limit</b> parameter.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </returns>
</xml>
