<xml>
    <brief>Retrieve information on a single geocache</brief>
    <issue-id>19</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Retrieve information on a single geocache.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='cache_code'>Unique code of the geocache</req>
    <opt name='langpref' default='en'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of ISO 639-1 language codes. This indicates the
        order of preference in which language will be chosen for fields like
        <b>name</b> and <b>description</b>.</p>

        <p>Please note, that you may also access caches' descriptions in all
        available languages. If you want to do this, you should use fields
        <b>names</b>, <b>descriptions</b> (etc.) instead of <b>name</b> and
        <b>description</b> (etc.).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='fields' default='code|name|location|type|status'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of field names which you are interested with.
        Selected fields will be included in the response. See below for the
        list of available fields.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='attribution_append' default='full'>
        <p>By default, OKAPI appends the value of <b>attribution_note</b> field to all the
        cache descriptions. If you would like to display the attribution note separately,
        you may use this parameter. Use one of the following values:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p><b>full</b> - OKAPI will append the attribution note to the descriptions of the
                geocache. The language of the note will match the language of the description
                (i.e. each value in <b>descriptions</b> may contain attribution notes in
                a different language).</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>none</b> - OKAPI will not append the attribution note to geocache
                descriptions. You will need to use the <b>attribution_note</b> instead
                (which also depends on the <b>langpref</b> parameter).</p>

                <p><b>Important note:</b> You are still <b>required</b> to display the
                <b>attribution_note</b> field in some other way.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>static</b> - OKAPI will append a "static" attribution note to the descriptions
                of the geocache. This might equal the "full" attribution note, but not necessarilly,
                since the "full" note may contain a current date
                (<a href='https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/178'>why?</a>),
                and the "static" note will not. This is implemented primarily for internal use
                (i.e. the replicate module). Usually you should not use it, because on some
                installations the static note will not be sufficient to meet the data license
                requirements.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name='lpc' default='10'>
        Log-entries per cache - the number of logs returned in the <b>latest_logs</b> field.
        This should be an integer or a special "all" value. Please note, that you must include
        the <b>latest_logs</b> field in <b>fields</b> in order to see the log entries.
    </opt>
    <opt name='log_fields' default='uuid|date|user|type|comment'>
        Pipe-separated list of log fields to include in the <b>latest_logs</b> field.
        For valid field names, see <b>logs/entry</b> method.
    </opt>
    <opt name='my_location'>
        <p>The reference point for cache distance and bearing calculation (typically - the user's location),
        in the "lat|lon" format. This parameter is required when accessing <b>distance</b> and/or <b>bearing</b>
        fields.</p>

        <p>Use positive numbers for latitudes in the northern hemisphere and
        longitudes in the eastern hemisphere (and negative for southern and
        western hemispheres accordingly). These are full degrees with a dot
        as a decimal point (ex. "54.3|22.3").</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name="user_uuid">
        <p>User'd ID. Required to access fields like <b>is_found</b> using <b>Level 1</b> Authentication.</p>

        <p>Please note that if you want to access private fields (like <b>my_notes</b>), then
        this parameter won't help you. You have to use <b>Level 3</b> Authentication instead.</p>

        <p>If you use <b>Level 3</b> Authentication, you shouldn't use this parameter. Or, to be exact:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>user_uuid</b> will be extracted from the Access Token you use. You don't have to provide it.</li>

            <li>If you provide <b>user_uuid</b>, then it HAS TO match your Access Token. If it doesn't, OKAPI
            will respond with HTTP 400 error.</li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of fields you have selected. Currently available fields:</p>

        <ul>
            <li><b>code</b> - unique Opencaching code of the geocache,</li>
            <li><b>name</b> - name of the geocache,</li>
            <li>
                <b>names</b> - a dictionary (language code => plain-text string) of
                names of the geocache (at this time, there will be only one language,
                but this may change in future),
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>location</b> - location of the cache in the "lat|lon" format
                (<i>lat</i> and <i>lon</i> are in full degrees with a dot as a decimal point),
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>type</b> - cache type. This might be <b>pretty much everything</b>,
                but there are some predefined types that you might want to treat
                in a special way (separate icons etc.). Primary types include:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Traditional</b>,</li>
                    <li><b>Multi</b>,</li>
                    <li><b>Quiz</b>,</li>
                    <li><b>Virtual</b>,</li>
                    <li><b>Event</b>,</li>
                    <li><i>(any other value is valid too)</i></li>
                </ul>
                <p><b>Event</b> is a peculiar type of geocache which is NOT a geocache
                at all, but it <b>is</b> stored as a geocache in OC database (this design
                decision is as old as the OC network itself!). Just keep in mind, that
                in case of Event Caches, some fields may have a little different meaning
                than you would tell by their name.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>status</b> - cache status. Valid cache status codes currently include:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Available</b> - Cache is available and ready for search,</li>
                    <li><b>Temporarily unavailable</b> - Cache is unavailable
                    (probably cannot be found) but may be restored,</li>
                    <li><b>Archived</b> - Cache is permanently unavailable (moved to the archives).</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>%OKAPI:infotag:ocde-specific% <b>needs_maintenance</b> - boolean, <b>true</b> if the geocache is
                known to be in poor condition, e.g. damaged. Usually there will be further
                explanations in the log entries.</p>

                <p>Please note that only OCDE-based Opencaching installations provide this
                information. ODPL-based sites will always return <b>false</b> here.</p>
            </li>
            <li><b>url</b> - URL of the cache's web page,</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>owner</b> - dictionary of:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>uuid</b> - geocache owner's user ID,</li>
                    <li><b>username</b> - name of the user,</li>
                    <li><b>profile_url</b> - URL of the user profile page,</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>gc_code</b> - Geocaching.com code (GC code) of the geocache
                <b>or null</b> if the cache is not listed on GC or the GC code is
                unknown.</p>

                <p>Please note that this information is supplied by cache owners
                and it is often missing, obsolete or otherwise incorrect.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>distance</b> - float, the distance to a cache, in meters.
                This requires <b>my_location</b> parameter to be provided.</p>

                <p>Please note, that sometimes it is faster to compute this
                yourself, on client-side, instead of querying OKAPI.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>bearing</b> - float, the absolute bearing to the cache, measured in
                degrees from north, <b>or null</b> if it cannot be calculated (i.e. when you
                are exactly at the target's location). This requires <b>my_location</b>
                parameter to be provided.</p>

                <p>Please note, that sometimes it is faster to compute this
                yourself, on client-side, instead of querying OKAPI.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>bearing2</b> - string, the absolute bearing to the cache, represented as
                a typical direction string of length of 1 or 2 characters (ex. "N", "NE", "E",
                "SE", etc.), or "n/a" if it cannot be calculated. This requires
                <b>my_location</b> parameter to be provided.</p>

                <p>Please note, that sometimes it is faster to compute this
                yourself, on client-side, instead of querying OKAPI.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>bearing3</b> - string, the absolute bearing to the cache, represented as
                a typical direction string of length of 1 or 2 or 3 characters (ex. "N", "NNE",
                "NE", "ENE", etc.), or "n/a" if it cannot be calculated. This requires
                <b>my_location</b> parameter to be provided.</p>

                <p>Please note, that sometimes it is faster to compute this
                yourself, on client-side, instead of querying OKAPI.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>is_found</b> - boolean, true if the user already found this cache.
                See also <b>found_status</b> parameter of the services/caches/search/all
                method.</p>

                <p>This field requires you to use the <b>user_uuid</b> parameter
                (or Level 3 Authentication). Please note, that this will also return <b>true</b>
                for attended Event Caches.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>is_not_found</b> - boolean, true if the user has
                submitted "Didn't find it" log entry for this cache.</p>

                <p>This field requires you to use the <b>user_uuid</b>
                parameter (or Level 3 Authentication).</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>is_watched</b> - boolean, true if the user is watching this cache. You
                may consider highlighting such geocaches in some fashion, as the users may use
                this functionality to temporarily mark geocaches of particular interest (i.e.
                geocaches they plan to find today).</p>

                <p>This is private data. You will need Level 3 Authentication
                to access this field.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>is_ignored</b> - boolean, true if the user is ignoring this cache. (See
                also <b>exclude_ignored</b> parameter of all search methods.)</p>

                <p>This is private data. You will need Level 3 Authentication
                to access this field.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>founds</b> - number of times the geocache was successfully found
                (or attended, in case of Event Caches),</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>notfounds</b> - number of times the geocache was not found
                (in case of Event Caches this will always be zero),</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>willattends</b> - in case of Event Caches, this is the number of
                "Will attend" log entries. In case of any other cache type, it will
                be <b>zero</b> (not null, for <a href='https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/233'>backward
                compatibility</a>),</p>
            </li>
            <li class='deprecated'>
                <b>size</b> - deprecated
                (<a href='https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/155'>why?</a>),
                use <b>size2</b> instead. Float (between 1 and 5), size rating of the container, or
                <b>null</b> if geocache does not have a container,
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>size2</b> - string indicating the size of the container, so called
                "size2 code". One of the following values:
                'none', 'nano', 'micro', 'small', 'regular', 'large', 'xlarge', 'other'.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>oxsize</b> - float (between 1 and 5) or null, this is a size rating
                variant, compatible with the one used by (former) OpenCaching.com site (and many
                Garmin GPS devices).</p>

                <p><b>Note:</b> The mapping is undocumented and may change without notice.</p>
                <p><b>Note:</b> Some of OC's size values cannot be properly mapped to <b>oxsize</b>,
                i.e. the 'other' size.</p>
            </li>
            <li><b>difficulty</b> - float (between 1 and 5), difficulty rating of the cache,</li>
            <li><b>terrain</b> - float (between 1 and 5), terrain rating of the cache,</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>trip_time</b> - float, approximate total amount of time needed to
                find the cache, in hours; this will usually include the time to reach the
                cache location <em>and</em> go back (from/to a parking spot, etc.);
                <b>null</b> if unknown,</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>trip_distance</b> - float, approximate total distance needed to
                find the cache, in kilometers; this will usually include the time to reach the
                cache location <em>and</em> go back (from/to a parking spot, etc.);
                <b>null</b> if unknown,</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>%OKAPI:infotag:ocpl-specific% <b>rating</b> - float (between 1 and 5), an
                overall rating of the cache, or <b>null</b> when the geocache does not have a
                sufficient amount of votes to have a rating.</p>

                <p><b>Notice:</b> Only OCPL-based Opencaching installations provide ratings for
                their geocaches. On OCDE-based installations, this field will always contain
                <b>null</b>.</p>

                <p><b>Notice:</b> Currently OCPL exposes cache ratings as integers only.
                OKAPI used floats here for forward-compatibility only. In other words, currently
                you can get 4.0 or 5.0 here, but not 4.5. This may change in the future though,
                without notice.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>%OKAPI:infotag:ocpl-specific% <b>rating_votes</b> - number of votes submitted
                for the rating of this cache.</p>

                <p><b>Notice:</b> Only OCPL-based Opencaching installations provide ratings for
                their geocaches. On OCDE-based installations, this field will always contain
                <b>0</b>.</p>
            </li>
            <li><b>recommendations</b> - number of recommendations for this cache,</li>
            <li>
                <b>req_passwd</b> - boolean; states if this cache requires a password
                in order to submit a "Found it" log entry,
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>short_description</b> - a plaintext string with a single line (very short)
                description of the cache (kind of a "tagline text"),
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>short_descriptions</b> - a dictionary (language code =&gt;
                plaintext string) of short cache descriptions,
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>description</b> - <a href='%OKAPI:docurl:html%'>HTML string</a>,
                description of the cache,
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>descriptions</b> - a dictionary (language code =&gt;
                <a href='%OKAPI:docurl:html%'>HTML string</a>) of cache descriptions,
            </li>
            <li class="deprecated">
                <b>hint</b> - <a href='%OKAPI:docurl:html%'>HTML-encoded</a>
                string, cache hints/spoilers; deprecated
                (<a href="https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/261">why?</a>),
                use <b>hint2</b> instead,
            </li>
            <li class="deprecated">
                <b>hints</b> - a dictionary (language code =&gt;
                <a href='%OKAPI:docurl:html%'>HTML-encoded</a> string) of cache hints/spoilers;
                deprecated, use hints2 instead,
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>hint2</b> - plain-text string, cache hints/spoilers; in general, hints
                should not be displayed to the user unless user specifically asks for them,
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>hints2</b> - a dictionary (language code =&gt;
                plain-text string) of cache hints/spoilers,
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>images</b> - list of dictionaries, each dictionary represents one
                image saved along the cache description; each dictionary has the
                following structure:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>uuid</b> - UUID of the image,</li>
                    <li><b>url</b> - URL of the image,</li>
                    <li><b>thumb_url</b> - URL of a small (thumb) version of the image,</li>
                    <li><b>caption</b> - plain-text string, caption of the image,</li>
                    <li>
                        <b>unique_caption</b> - plain-text string, to be used as a filename
                        for Garmin's crappy images implementation (currently, they get image
                        caption from the image's filename itself),
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>is_spoiler</b> - boolean, if <b>true</b> then the image is
                        a spoiler image and should not be displayed to the user unless
                        the user explicitly asks for it,
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>%OKAPI:infotag:ocde-specific% <b>preview_image</b> - On OCDE-based
                installations, owners may select one of the <b>images</b>
                (see above) as a preview image. You are encouraged to display it as a 'teaser'
                for this cache. On OCPL-based installations this functionality is disabled and you
                will always get the <b>null</b> value here.</p>

                <p>The value of <b>preview_image</b> is either <b>null</b> or a dictionary describing
                an image. The structure of this dictionary is the same as of a single entry on
                the <b>images</b> list described above.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>attr_acodes</b> - unordered list of OKAPI geocache-attribute IDs (A-codes) with
                which the cache was tagged. Use the <b>attrs</b> module to retrieve information on
                these attributes.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>attrnames</b> - if you don't want to dig into <b>attr_acodes</b> just now, then
                you can use these as a simple alternative. <b>attrnames</b> is an unordered list of
                names of the attributes with which the cache was tagged; the language will be
                selected based on the <b>langpref</b> parameter.
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>attribution_note</b> - the proper attribution note for the cache listing according
                to the local OC site's Data License. By default, this note is also appended to geocache
                descriptions (see the <b>attribution_append</b> parameter).</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>latest_logs</b> - a couple of latest log entries in the cache.
                The format is the same as the one returned by the services/logs/logs method.</p>

                <p>Notice: The number of logs returned can be set with the <b>lpc</b> option.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>my_notes</b> - user's notes on the cache, in plain-text, or <b>null</b>
                if user hadn't defined any notes.</p>

                <p>This field requires you to use the <b>Level 3</b> Authentication.</p>
            </li>
            <li><b>trackables_count</b> - a total number of trackables hidden within the cache.</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>trackables</b> - list of dictionaries, each dictionary represents one
                trackable hidden within the cache container; each dictionary has the
                following structure:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>code</b> - code of the trackable,</li>
                    <li><b>name</b> - plain text name of the trackable,</li>
                    <li>
                        <b>url</b> - trackable's own webpage address <b>or null</b>, if OKAPI
                        cannot automatically determine this address.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li id="ret_alt_wpts">
                <p><b>alt_wpts</b> - list of alternate/additional waypoints associated
                with this geocache. Each item is a dictionary of the following structure:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>name</b> - plain-text, short, unique "codename" for the waypoint,</li>
                    <li><b>location</b> - location of the waypoint in the "lat|lon" format
                        (<i>lat</i> and <i>lon</i> are in full degrees with a dot as a decimal point),</li>
                    <li>
                        <p><b>type</b> - string, unique identifier for the type of waypoint;
                        one of the following:</p>

                        <ul>
                            <li><b>parking</b>, <b>path</b>, <b>stage</b>, <b>physical-stage</b>,
                            <b>virtual-stage</b>, <b>final</b>, <b>poi</b>, <b>other</b> - used by
                            OC itself, for detailed descriptions of these you'll have to refer to
                            external Opencaching documenation,</li>

                            <li><b>user-coords</b> - extra coordinates supplied <i>by the user who
                            had found the cache</i> (NOT the owner of the cache), most probably
                            pointing to the final location of the cache (e.g. a quiz cache);
                            this type of waypoint is available only in some installations and only
                            if you're using Level 3 Authentication,</li>

                            <li>more types may be added at any moment; unknown types should be
                            treated as <b>other</b>.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>type_name</b> - string, the human-readable name of the waypoint type,
                        e.g. "Parking area" or "Final location"; the language will be selected
                        based on the langpref argument,
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p><b>sym</b> - string, one of commonly recognized waypoint symbol
                        names, originally introduced by Garmin in their devices and GPX
                        files (e.g. "Flag, Green" or "Parking Area").</p>

                        <p>These symbol codes are only suggestions. They are understood by
                        Garmin-related software and devices. If you don't know how to display such
                        symbols, you are welcome to use any symbol you'd like in your
                        application.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li><b>description</b> - plain-text longer description of the waypoint.</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>country</b> - name of the country the cache is placed in;
                may be empty ("") if the country is unknown.</p>

                <p><b>Note:</b> This data is user-supplied and is not validated in
                any way. Consider using external geocoding services instead. Also,
                currently you have no way of knowing in which language it will appear
                in (but it *may* start to vary on the value of your <b>langpref</b>
                parameter in the future).</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>state</b> - name of the state the cache is placed in;
                may be empty ("") if the state is unknown.</p>

                <p><b>Note:</b> On some installations this data is user-supplied and
                is not validated in any way. Other installations calculate it from
                cache coordinates but may have problems in border regions.
                Consider using external geocoding services instead. Also,
                currently you have no way of knowing in which language it will appear
                in (but it *may* start to vary on the value of your <b>langpref</b>
                parameter in the future).</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>protection_areas</b> - list of dictionaries, each representing a
                protection area in which the cache probably is located; each dictionary
                has the following structure:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>type</b> - the type of the protection area, e.g.
                    "National Nature Reserve",</li>
                    <li><b>name</b> - the name of the protection area, e.g.
                    "East Dartmoor Woods and Heaths".</li>
                </ul>
                <p>The types and names currently are in a local language of the OC site but
                may be translated depending on the <b>langpref</b> parameter in the future.</p>

                <p>Note that this information is not authoritative. It may be outdated
                or incomplete, and it is completely missing on some OC installations.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>last_found</b> - date and time (ISO 8601) when the
                geocache was last found <b>or null</b> when it hasn't been yet found.</p>

                <p>Note, that some Opencaching servers don't store the exact times along
                with the log entries.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>last_modified</b> - date and time (ISO 8601) when the
                geocache was last modified (changed status, attributes, etc.),
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>date_created</b> - date and time (ISO 8601) when the
                geocache was listed at the Opencaching site. For OCDE-based installations
                this is the date when it was published, while for ODPL installations it is the
                date when it was originally submitted. These dates differ if the
                geocache is prepared and then published later.
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>date_hidden</b> - date and time (ISO 8601) when:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>the geocache was first hidden (for physical caches), or </li>
                    <li>the geocache was first published (for virtual caches), or</li>
                    <li>the event takes place (for event caches),</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <!-- Note: I think cache uuids should not be ever revealed to the public.
            We have already one universally unique key - the cache code. It is uncommon
            to have multiple universally unique keys. -->
            <li>
                <b>internal_id</b> - internal ID of the cache (<b>do not</b> use
                this, unless you know what you're doing; use the "code" as an identifier).
            </li>
        </ul>

        <p>For example, for <i>geocache?cache_code=OP3D96&amp;fields=type</i>
        query, the result might look something link this:</p>

        <pre>{"type": "Traditional"}</pre>

        <p>If given cache code does not exist, the method will
        respond with an HTTP 400 error.</p>
    </returns>
</xml>
