<xml>
    <brief>Get information on this OKAPI installation</brief>
    <issue-id>14</issue-id>
    <desc>
        Retrieve some basic information about this OKAPI installation.
    </desc>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of the following structure:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <b>site_url</b> - URL of the Opencaching site which is running
                the OKAPI installation (usually this looks like
                "http://www.opencaching.<i>xx</i>/", where <b>xx</b> is a top
                level domain of a country).
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>okapi_base_url</b> - the <i>recommended</i> base URL to be used when
                accessing this OKAPI installation (it should be used as a prefix when
                constructing method URLs),
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>okapi_base_urls</b> - a list of <i>all</i> base URLs allowed to be used
                when calling OKAPI methods in this installation.</p>
                
                <p>In theory, once a new base URL appears on this list, it should never
                disappear (it should be allowed to use it forever). However, for various
                reasons, we cannot guarantee it will indeed be so. Clients SHOULD use the
                recommended base URL provided in the <b>okapi_base_url</b> field.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>site_name</b> - international name of the Opencaching site,
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>okapi_version_number</b> - integer; the version number of
                the OKAPI instance installed on this Opencaching site, <b>or
                null</b>, if the version number could not be determined.</p>

                <p>The version number will be incremented with each new
                revision of OKAPI (that is, after every commit to OKAPI
                repository).</p>

                <p>You can use it to check if this OKAPI installation will be
                compatbile with your client application: if the number is
                equal to or higher than the one you have expected, then it will
                be compatible.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>okapi_revision</b> - this is an older alias of
                <b>okapi_version_number</b>.</p>

                <p>For a number of years, OKAPI used SVN for version control.
                SVN uses integers for commit IDs. Hence, version numbers and
                revision numbers were exactly the same thing. (In fact, the
                <b>okapi_version_number</b> field has been introduced only
                <i>after</i> OKAPI has been migrated to Git.)</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>git_revision</b> - string, the Git revision of the OKAPI
                project installed on this Opencaching site, <b>or null</b>,
                when it could not be determined.
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>registration_url</b> - URL of the Opencaching site's general
                page for registering a new user account.
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>mobile_registration_url</b> - URL of the Opencaching site's
                page for registering a new user account, which is optimized
                for small mobile displays, <b>or null</b> if no separate
                mobile-optimized page exists.
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>image_max_upload_size</b> - the maximum size (in bytes)
                of images which can be uploaded via this OKAPI installation.
                Larger images will be <em>rejected</em>. This value may change
                in time.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>image_rcmd_max_pixels</b> - the maximum pixel count
                (width * height) of uploaded images, which will be accepted
                without triggering server-side shrinking. (You MAY submit
                larger images, but they will be downscaled.) This value may
                change in time.</p>

                <p>Note: Do not rely on images <em>retrieved</em> from this OC
                site to fit this restriction. Larger images may have been
                uploaded in the past, or by other means than OKAPI.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </returns>
</xml>