<xml>
    <brief>Authorize the Request Token</brief>
    <issue-id>22</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Unlike other methods, the <b>authorize</b> method is to be executed
        inside the User's browser. Consumer's role is to <b>redirect</b> the User to
        this URL, then wait if he ever comes back with a callback request.</p>
        <p>Once the User is redirected to this URL, several things will happen:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>If he's not already logged in, he will be asked to do so.</li>
            <li>OKAPI will check if the User haven't previously granted your
            application access to his Opencaching account.</li>
            <li>If User did not previously authorize your application, OKAPI
            will display an "Authorization Request" form to the User. User
            will be presented with a choice to allow or not to allow your
            application access to his account.</li>
            <li>If the User clicks one of these two options ("allow" or "don't allow"),
            he's browser will be redirected to the <b>callback_url</b> you defined
            while getting your Request Token.
            If you did not provide a callback (in other word, provided "oob"),
            user will be redirected to a default "authorized" page, where he
            will be presented with an oauth_verifier (user will know it
            by name of a <b>PIN code</b>) and asked to type it into your application.</li>
        </ul>
    </desc>
    <req name='oauth_token'>
        Consult <a href='https://oauth.net/core/1.0a/'>OAuth 1.0a documentation</a> for details.
    </req>
    <opt name='interactivity' default='minimal'>
        <p>Currently, one of the following values:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>minimal</b> - OKAPI will use as little interactivity as it can.
            It will assume that currently logged in user is the user which you
            want to authorize. If the user has already authorized your application,
            he will not be asked to do this again.</li>
            <li><b>confirm_user</b> - even if a user is logged in, OKAPI will NOT
            assume that this is the user who wants to be authorized. OKAPI will
            offer to authorize a different user (e.g. by automatically logging out
            the user who is currently logged in).</li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name='langpref'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of ISO 639-1 language codes. This indicates the
        order of preference in which the language will be chosen for the authorization page.</p>
        <p>By default, OKAPI will display the page in the primary native language of local
        Opencaching installation.</p>
    </opt>
    <returns>
        <p>Technically, an HTTP 302 Redirect - it will direct user's browser to the OKAPI apps
        authorization page.</p>
        <p>Whether with callback_url or with a manual user entry - you will get
        your <b>oauth_verifier</b>, which allows you to continue the 3-legged
        authentication dance.</p>
        <p>If you used <b>callback_url</b>, you should wait for an HTTP GET request,
        with one additional GET parameter appended:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>oauth_token</b> - the Request Token that has been just authorized,</li>
            <li><b>oauth_verifier</b> - the PIN code required to get an Access Token.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>OR, in case when user denied the request:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>oauth_token</b> - the Request Token,</li>
            <li><b>error</b> - codename of an error - <b>access_denied</b>.</li>
        </ul>
    </returns>
</xml>
