<xml>
    <brief>Add an image to a log entry</brief>
    <issue-id>395</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Attach a new image to an existing log entry.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='log_uuid'>
        <p>ID of the log entry to which the image will be attached. The user
        of your Access Token must be the author of this log entry.</p>
    </req>
    <req name='image'>
        <p>Base64-encoded image file; must be in JPEG, PNG or GIF format.</p>

        <p>There are some <em>dynamic</em> limits on the file size and dimensions
        of uploaded images; you should query them via the
        <a href="../apisrv/installation.html">service/apiserv/installation</a>
        method before uploading. The image may be shrunk, rotated, EXIF-stripped
        or otherwise be processed before it is stored.</p>
    </req>
    <opt name='caption'>
        <p>Plain-text string, a caption of the image. Captions are usually
        displayed along with the images.</p>

        <p>You MAY allow your user to attempt submitting anything here (including
        an empty caption), but you should always be prepared to receive
        <b>false</b> in the <b>success</b> field due to restrictions on what
        captions are accepted.</p>

        <p>Note: Some OC sites support only BMP (Basic Multilingual Plane) Unicode
        characters on some database fields. If you submit characters from outside of
        the BMP plane (known as "supplementary planes", they include characters such
        as smiley symbols), then keep in mind that your text might be saved garbled.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='is_spoiler' default='false'>
        <p>Set this to <b>true</b> to indicate that the submitted image contains
        hints for finding the geocache, i.e. it shows the hiding place. Spoiler images
        usually will not be shown to users by default, but replaced by a clickable
        placeholder or caption that leads to the image.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='position'>
        <p>Indicates the wanted position of this image on the log entry's list
        of images. By default, new images will be appended to the end of this
        list.</p>

        <p>The value is 0-based (so, if you want this image to be displayed as
        the first one, you should use the 0 value). The position of the image
        which currently takes the given spot will be shifted downwards (you can
        never replace any image using this method). If you provide an invalid
        value (e.g. greater than the number of images), then OKAPI will try to
        use the its best guess (e.g. append the image to the end).</p>

        <p>Note: Some installations will ignore this option and always append
        new images to the end of the list.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='langpref' default='en'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of ISO 639-1 language codes. This indicates the
        order of preference in which language will be chosen for error messages.</p>
    </opt>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of the following structure:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <b>success</b> - <b>true</b>, if the image was submitted successfully,
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>message</b> - plain-text string, a message for the user,
                which acknowledges success or describes an error (usually you
                want to display this only when <b>success</b> is <b>false</b>),
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>image_uuid</b> - ID of the appended image, or <b>null</b> in
                case of an error,
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>position</b> - 0-based position of the appended image
                on the log entry's list of images; <b>null</b> in case of
                an error.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </returns>
</xml>
