<xml>
    <brief>Search for nearest geocaches</brief>
    <issue-id>17</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Find the nearest geocaches. Unless overriden, results are ordered by the distance from
        the given center point.</p>

        <p>Usually you will want to use search_and_retrieve method instead of this one.
        This way, you can get much more data in <b>one request</b>.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='center'>
        <p>The center point (typically - the user's location), in the
        "lat|lon" format.</p>

        <p>Use positive numbers for latitudes in the northern hemisphere and
        longitudes in the eastern hemisphere (and negative for southern and
        western hemispheres accordingly). These are full degrees with a dot
        as a decimal point (ex. "54.3|22.3").</p>
    </req>
    <opt name='radius'>
        <p>Maximal distance (from the center point) for the cache to
        be included in the results. Unlike in most other places, this
        distance is given <b>in kilometers</b> instead of meters
        (it may contain a floating point though).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='location_source' default='default-coords'>
        <p>In general, this parameter should take the same value as in the
        <a href="%OKAPI:methodargref:services/caches/formatters/gpx#location_source%">
        services/caches/formatters/gpx</a> method, but currently <u>only two values are
        supported</u>: <b>default-coords</b> and <b>alt_wpt:user-coords</b>.</p>

        <p>Allows you to search among alternate locations of the geocache,
        instead of the default one. Particularily useful with <b>alt_wpt:user-coords</b>
        alternate waypoint.</p>

        <p>Please note, that if you plan on using this option in conjunction
        with <b>search_and_retrieve</b> method, then you'd probably want to use
        the same option in your <i>retr_method</i> too (if available).</p>
    </opt>
    <import-params method='services/caches/search/all'/>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>Same format as in the search/all method. The <b>more</b> key will
        be skipped when no <b>radius</b> argument is given.</p>
    </returns>
</xml>
