<xml>
    <brief>Retrieve information on a single log entry</brief>
    <issue-id>108</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Retrieve information on a single log entry.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='log_uuid'>UUID of the log entry</req>
    <opt name='fields' default='date|user|type|comment'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of field names which you are interested with.
        Selected fields will be included in the response. See below fot the list
        of available fields.</p>
    </opt>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of fields you have selected. Currently available fields:</p>

        <ul>
            <li><b>uuid</b> - unique ID of the log entry,</li>
            <li><b>cache_code</b> - code of the cache which the log entry refers to,</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>date</b> - date and time (ISO 8601) when the log entry was submitted.</p>
                <p>Please note that log entries often contain dates only (with the times
                truncated to midnight, as in the local timezone). In such cases, you may
                want to avoid displaying the time. You may assume that if the <b>date</b>
                value contains the "00:00:00" string, then it is date-only.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>user</b> - a dictionary:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>uuid</b> - ID of the user (author of the log entry),</li>
                    <li><b>username</b> - name of the user (who submitted the log entry),</li>
                    <li><b>profile_url</b> - URL of the profile page of the user,</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>type</b> - string; log type. One of the values documented
                below.</p>

                <p>Primary types, commonly used by all Opencaching installations:</p>

                <ul>
                    <li>"Found it" - a user found the cache (Non-Event caches).</li>
                    <li>"Didn't find it" - a user searched for, but couldn't find the cache (Non-Event caches).</li>
                    <li>"Comment".</li>
                    <li>"Will attend" - a user is planning to attend the event (for Event caches only).</li>
                    <li>"Attended" - a user has attended the event (for Event caches only).</li>
                </ul>

                <p>Types which indicate a change of state of the geocache or confirm the
                state at the given time (used only by some Opencaching installations):</p>

                <ul>
                    <li>
                        "Temporarily unavailable" - log of this type indicates that the status
                        of the cache was changed to "Temporarily unavailable" at that time, or it
                        was confirmed as "Temporarily unavailable". Most probably the cache was
                        not available to be found at that time, but it was expected to be
                        repaired soon (and then, "Ready to search" log type would be submitted).
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        "Ready to search" - log of this type indicates that the status of this
                        cache was changed back to "Available", or it was confirmed as "Available".
                        After some period of not being available the cache became ready to be found
                        again.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        "Archived" - log of this type indicates that the status of this cache was
                        changed to "Archived" at this point in time. This usually means that the
                        cache could not be found anymore at this time, and it was not expected to
                        be repaired any time soon.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        "Locked" - the status of this cache was changed to "Locked" (similar to
                        "Archived", but no more "Found it" log entries are allowed on "Locked"
                        caches).
                    </li>
                </ul>

                <p>Other types (used only by some Opencaching installations):</p>

                <ul>
                    <li>"Needs maintenance" - the user stated that the cache was
                        in need of maintenance.</li>
                    <li>"Maintenance performed" - the cache owner stated that he
                        has performed the maintenance.</li>
                    <li>"Moved" - the cache was moved to a different location.</li>
                    <li>"OC Team comment" - a comment made by the official OC Team
                        member.</li>
                    <li><i>(to be continued)</i> - this list MAY expand in time!
                        Your application should accept unknown log types (you may
                        treat them as "Comment"s).</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>oc_team_entry</b> - <b>true</b> if the log entry was made by an
                official OC team member and marked as administrative log; <b>false</b> if it has
                not been marked.</p>
                <p>Note: <b>false</b> does NOT mean that it is no administrative log,
                because this flag can be missing for (mostly old) admin logs.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>was_recommended</b> - <b>true</b> if the author included his recommendation
                in this log entry,</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>needs_maintenance2</b> - log entry authors may include an
                additional report on the condition of the geocache at the given date
                (indicate if the cache needed maintenance).</p>

                <p>You could say that the values of this field reflect the values of the
                <b>needs_maintenance2</b> parameter used to submit the log entry (however,
                the log itself might have been submitted through other means). Possible
                values are:</p>

                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <b>true</b> - in the author's opinion, the geocache was in poor
                        condition and needed maintenance,
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>false</b> - in the author's opinion, the geocache was in good
                        or acceptable condition and did not need maintenance (anymore),
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>null</b> - the author did not include any report on the
                        condition of the geocache.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li><b>comment</b> - <a href='%OKAPI:docurl:html%'>HTML string</a>, text entered
                with the log entry,</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>images</b> - list of dictionaries, each dictionary represents one
                image saved along with the log; each dictionary has the following
                structure:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>uuid</b> - UUID of the image,</li>
                    <li><b>url</b> - URL of the image,</li>
                    <li><b>thumb_url</b> - URL of a small (thumb) version of the image,</li>
                    <li><b>caption</b> - plain-text string, caption of the image,</li>
                    <li><b>is_spoiler</b> - boolean, if <b>true</b> then the image is
                        a spoiler image and should not be displayed to the user unless
                        the user explicitly asks for it.</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>internal_id</b> - undocumented, you <u>should not</u> use
                this unless you really know you need to. Internal IDs are
                <b>not</b> unique across various OKAPI installations.
                Try to use UUIDs instead.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>

        <p>Note, that some fields can change in time (users can edit/delete
        their log entries).</p>

        <p>If given log entry does not exist, the method will
        respond with an HTTP 400 error.</p>
    </returns>
</xml>