<xml>
    <brief>Submit a log entry</brief>
    <issue-id>42</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Submit a log entry for the geocache. Please note, that you won't be
        able to use this method until you learn to handle OAuth.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='cache_code'>
        <p>Code of the geocache.</p>
    </req>
    <req name='logtype'>
        <p>Type of an entry. This should be one of:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <i>Will attend</i>, <i>Attended</i> or <i>Comment</i> for Event caches;
            </li>
            <li>
                <i>Found it</i>, <i>Didn't find it</i> or <i>Comment</i> for all other
                cache types.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </req>
    <opt name='comment'>
        <p>Text to be submitted with the log entry.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='comment_format' default='auto'>
        <p>Indicates the format of your <b>comment</b>. Three values allowed:
        <b>auto</b>, <b>html</b> or <b>plaintext</b>. Usually, you should <b>not</b>
        use the <b>auto</b> option, because its exact behavior is unspecified
        and may depend on the installation
        (<a href='https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/124'>more info</a>).</p>

        <p><b>Important note:</b> Unfortunatelly, some OC nodes don't support this
        parameter properly - regardless of what you choose, you may end up with
        <a href='https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/324'>unexpected
        results</a>. Currently, there is nothing OKAPI developers can do
        to fix this, but you should use this parameter either way (to indicate how
        you <b>expect</b> it to behave) - we hope this will be fixed, eventually.</p>

        <p><b>Important note:</b> The subset of allowed HTML elements is left undefined
        and may change in the future. For future-compatibility, you should use only
        basic formatting tags.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='when'>
        <p>A date and time string. This should be in ISO 8601 format (currently any
        format acceptable by PHP's <a href='http://php.net/manual/function.strtotime.php'>strtotime</a>
        function also will do, but most of them don't handle time zones properly,
        try to use ISO 8601!). You MAY and are encouraged to omit the time and just
        submit a date (yyyy-mm-dd) if the time is unknown or shall not be disclosed.</p>

        <p>Indicates when the cache was found. If given, the log will be published
        with the given date and time. If not, log will be published using the current
        date and time. If only the date is given, OKAPI will publish the log in a way
        which most closely resembles "no time given"
        (<a href="https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/issues/358">more info</a>).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='password'>
        <p>Some caches require a password in order to submit a "Found it" log entry.
        You may check if this cache requires password with <b>req_passwd</b> field
        of the services/caches/geocache method.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='langpref' default='en'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of ISO 639-1 language codes. This indicates the
        order of preference in which language will be chosen for error messages.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='on_duplicate' default='silent_success'>
        <p>How should OKAPI react when you are trying to submit a duplicate entry?
        One of the following values:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>silent_success</b> - try to respond with success=true, but don't
            add a new log entry (existing log_uuid will be returned),</li>
            <li><b>user_error</b> - respond with success=false and a proper user message,</li>
            <li><b>continue</b> - don't detect duplicates (note, that this will still
            fail in some cases, i.e. when you're trying to submit a "Found it" entry for an
            already found cache).</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Note, that duplicate detection may take the <b>when</b> parameter into account.
        When you don't supply it, "when" is generated for you. This means that you may
        have to supply the "when" parameter if you want duplicate detection to work.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='rating'>
        <p>An integer in range between 1 and 5 - user's optional rating of a found cache.</p>
        <p>Important: <b>logtype</b> has to be "Found it" in order to use this argument.</p>
        <p>Note: You should allow your user to <b>not</b> rate a found cache.</p>
        <p>Note: Currently, some OC installations do not support cache ratings. On such installations
        user's rating will be <b>ignored</b> (if you include the rating, log entry will be posted
        successfully, but rating will be ignored).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='recommend' default='false'>
        <p>Set to <b>true</b> if the user wants to recommend this cache.</p>
        <p>Important: <b>logtype</b> has to be "Found it" or "Attended" in order to
        use this argument. However, some installations do not support recommending
        event caches (if you include a recommendation, the log entry will be posted
        successfully, but the recommendation will be <b>ignored</b>).</p>
        <p>Recommending may only succeed when the user meets certain criteria
        set on him by the OC site. If criteria are not met, the request will
        end with user error (HTTP 200, success=false).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='needs_maintenance' default='false'>
        <p>Set to <b>true</b> if the user thinks that the cache needs some special attension
        of its owner. Users should describe the reason for maintenance in their comments.</p>
        <p>Note: Depending on OC installation and user's log entry type, OKAPI may actually
        publish two separate log entries when you check this flag (one of them with empty
        comment). Even then, you will still receive only one UUID reference (pointing to
        only one of those entries). Moreover, on some OC servers this flag might be
        <b>completely ignored</b> (not all OC servers support this feature).</p>
        <p>Note: Currently, this is not allowed for Event Caches (you will get a HTTP 200
        "user friendly" response).</p>
    </opt>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of the following structure:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>success</b> - true, if the log entry was submitted successfully,</li>
            <li><b>message</b> - plain-text string, a message for the user, which acknowledges success
                or describes an error (usually you want to display this only when success is false),</li>
            <li><b>log_uuid</b> - ID of the newly created log entry, <b>or null</b>
                in case of an error.</li>
        </ul>
    </returns>
</xml>