<xml>
    <brief>Search for caches and retrieve formatted results</brief>
    <issue-id>18</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>We think that searching and retrieving data are two different things
        and that's why they were cleanly separated in the documentation (put in
        separate methods). This was done primarily to keep the docs clean.
        This method allows you to do a quick search+retrieve task in one request.</p>
        <p>All services/caches/search/* methods respond with a list of cache codes.
        Then you have to use other method (like services/caches/geocaches) to
        retrieve the names and locations, based on those cache codes. The
        <b>search_and_retrieve</b> method allows you to do these two steps in one
        method call.</p>
        <p>First, you have to choose both methods and their parameters - one method
        which returns the cache codes, and the other one, that responds
        with additional data for the given caches.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='search_method'>
        <p>Name of the search method (begin with "services/").</p>
        <p>E.g. <i>services/caches/search/nearest</i>.</p>
    </req>
    <req name='search_params'>
        <p>JSON-formatted dictionary of parameters to be passed on
        to the search method.</p>
        <p>E.g. <i>{"center": "49|19", "status": "Available"}</i>.</p>
    </req>
    <req name='retr_method'>
        <p>Name of the retrieval method (begin with "services/").</p>
        <p>E.g. <i>services/caches/geocaches</i>.</p>
    </req>
    <req name='retr_params'>
        <p>JSON-formatted dictionary of parameters to be passed on
        to the retrieval method.</p>
        <p>E.g. <i>{"fields": "name|location|type"}</i></p>
        <p>The method will be called with one additional parameter - <b>cache_codes</b>.
        These will be the cache codes collected from the results of the search method.</p>
    </req>
    <req name='wrap'>
        <p>Boolean.</p>
        <ul>
            <li>If <b>true</b>, then results will be wrapped in an additional
            object, in order to include any additional data received along with the
            search_method response (i.e. the <b>more</b> value).</li>
            <li>If <b>false</b>, then this method will return exactly what the
            <b>retr_method</b> will respond with.</li>
        </ul>
    </req>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>If <b>wrap</b> is <b>true</b>, then the method will return a
        dictionary of the following structure:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>results</b> - anything the retrival method
            responds with (as long as it's not an error).</li>
            <li>any extra keys and values received as a response of
            the search_method (i.e. the <b>more</b> variable).</li>
        </ul>
        <p>If <b>wrap</b> is <b>false</b>, then the method will return
        anything the retrieval methods responds with (along with its HTTP headers).</p>
        <p><b>Example:</b></p>
        <pre>search_and_retrieve<br/>?search_method=services/caches/search/bbox<br/>&amp;search_params={"bbox":"49|19|50|20","limit":"1"}<br/>&amp;retr_method=services/caches/geocaches<br/>&amp;retr_params={"fields":"location"}<br/>&amp;wrap=false</pre>
        <p>Possible output:<br/><code>{"OP205A": {"location": "49.572417|19.525867"}}</code></p>
        <p>The same example with <i>wrap=true</i> would return:<br/><code>{"results": {"OP205A": {"location": "49.572417|19.525867"}}, "more": true}</code></p>
    </returns>
</xml>