<xml>
    <brief>Retrieve ZIP file for Garmin devices</brief>
    <issue-id>99</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Produce a ZIP file with content compatible with Geocaching-enabled Garmin
        GPS devices. The general idea is, <b>you should <u>extract</u> the contents</b> of the ZIP
        file directly <b>into the root directory</b> of your Garmin's internal memory storage
        (currently it doesn't work if you extract the data to the external MicroSD card). The device
        will then be filled with all the data we are currently able to fill it with.</p>
        <p>Currently, the ZIP file will contain GPX file and all JPEG images associated
        with the chosen geocaches. Options for the GPX file are fixed, use the
        services/caches/formatters/gpx method if
        you want a custom-tailored GPX file.</p>
        <p><b>Important note:</b> The contents of the returned ZIP archive may change in the
        future. You should not parse the contents, nor assume that they have any specific
        structure.</p>
        <p><b>Important note:</b> We might be increasing required authentication level for
        this method to level 2 or 3. You should be prepared for that. Use the highest authentication
        level you've got. Also, if you want the GPX file to include <b>personal data (like user's notes)</b>,
        you have to use Level 3 Authentication anyway.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='cache_codes'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of cache codes which you are interested in.
        No more than 50 codes are allowed. (This limit is smaller than usual, because
        we're afraid about the sizes of ZIP files produced.)
        This CAN be an empty string (it will still result in a valid ZIP file).</p>
    </req>
    <opt name='langpref' default='en'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of ISO 639-1 language codes. This indicates the
        order of preference in which language will be chosen for GPX entities.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='images' default='all'>
        <p>One of the following values:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>none</b> - no images will be included in the result,</li>
            <li><b>all</b> - all images will be included in the result,</li>
            <li><b>spoilers</b> - only spoiler images will be included in the result,</li>
            <li><b>nonspoilers</b> - only non-spoiler images will be included in the result.</li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name='caches_format' default='gpx'>
        <p><b>Important note:</b> This is a <b>BETA</b> parameter. It may change
        in a backward-incompatible manner, or it may even be removed.</p>

        <p>This parameter allows you to change the format of the geocache files
        embedded within the returned archive. One of the following values:</p>

        <ul>
            <li><b>gpx</b> - (default) use GPX files. The safest choice - these
            will work with all Garmin devices, but you might want to switch to
            the GGZ format to get a better performance.</li>

            <li><b>ggz</b> - if set, GGZ files will be used instead of GPX files.
            Fewer devices support GGZ format, but if your device does, then using
            them can give you a much better performance. See
            <a href="%OKAPI:methodref:services/caches/formatters/ggz%">services/caches/formatters/ggz</a>
            method for more information on the GGZ format.</li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name="location_source" default='default-coords'>
        Same as in the <a href="%OKAPI:methodargref:services/caches/formatters/gpx#location_source%">
        services/caches/formatters/gpx</a> method.
    </opt>
    <opt name="location_change_prefix" default="#">
        Same as in the <a href="%OKAPI:methodargref:services/caches/formatters/gpx#location_change_prefix%">
        services/caches/formatters/gpx</a> method.
    </opt>
    <returns>
        <p>ZIP file. You should extract it's contents directly into the root
        directory of your Garmin's internal memory storage.</p>
    </returns>
</xml>