<xml>
    <brief>Retrieve geocaches in GPX format</brief>
    <issue-id>40</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>Produces a standards-compliant Geocaching GPX file.</p>
        <p>Unlike the services/caches/geocaches method responses, GPX files cannot
        contain names and descriptions in separate multiple languages. This method
        will attempt to choose the best language based on your preference
        (see <b>langpref</b> argument).</p>
        <p>Remember that a full-blown GPX file is much larger than a basic one.
        This method can produce many various types of GPX files. The simplest list of
        waypoints takes ~50 times less space than the same list with cache descriptions
        and log entries included.</p>
        <p>Note, that GPX files may contain <a href='%OKAPI:docurl:html%'>unvalidated
        HTML</a>.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='cache_codes'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of cache codes which you are interested in.
        No more than 500 codes are allowed. This CAN be an empty string (it will
        result in an empty, but valid, GPX file). All invalid cache codes will
        be skipped without any notice!</p>
    </req>
    <opt name='langpref' default='en'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of ISO 639-1 language codes. This indicates the
        order of preference in which language will be chosen for GPX entities.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='ns_ground' default='false'>
        Boolean. If <b>true</b> then response will include
        <a href='http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0/1/cache.xsd'>Groundspeak's
        GPX extension</a>. This namespace declares an extra &lt;cache&gt; element
        used by <a href='http://www.geocaching.com/'>geocaching.com</a> and <b>many others</b>.
        This namespace was initially associatied with geocaching.com, but now seems to
        be used in every geocaching GPX file. You probably want to have it.
    </opt>
    <opt name='ns_gsak' default='false'>
        <p>Boolean. If <b>true</b> then response will include
        <a href='http://www.gsak.net/xmlv1/5/gsak.xsd'>GSAK GPX extension</a>.
        This namespace declares an extra &lt;wptExtension&gt; element,
        which allows including "waypoint inheritance" information (parent-child relations)
        via its &lt;Parent&gt; element. This in turn allows us to include
        "alternate waypoints" in the response.</p>

        <p>This feature was once supported by <a href='http://www.gsak.net/'>GSAK</a>
        application only, but currently many applications recognize it. As far as we
        know, it became a "de facto" standard for expressing "alternate waypoints".</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='ns_ox' default='false'>
        <p>Boolean. If <b>true</b> then response will include Garmin's
        <a href='https://github.com/opencaching/okapi/blob/master/etc/nsox.xsd'>OpenCaching.com
        GPX extension</a>. This namespace declares an extra &lt;opencaching&gt; element
        used by Garmin's (former) <b>OpenCaching.com</b> site.
        The element includes information on cache difficulty, ratings, tags and images.</p>

        <p>OpenCaching.com no longer exists, but its XML namespace is still used by many
        applications (and not only the Garmin ones, e.g. see
        <a href='http://help.locusmap.eu/topic/how-to-use-gcvotes-functionality-with-opencaching'>here</a>).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='images' default='descrefs:nonspoilers'>
        <p>Which images to include (and how to include them). One of the following values:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>none</b> - no images will be included,</li>
            <li><b>descrefs:thumblinks</b> - all images will be included as "thumbnail"
                &lt;img&gt; references at the end of each cache description, with a
                replacement image used for spoilers; the thumbnails are linked to the
                large images,</li>
            <li><b>descrefs:nonspoilers</b> - all non-spoiler images will be included
                as &lt;img&gt; references at the end of each cache description,</li>
            <li><b>descrefs:all</b> - all images will be included (including spoilers)
                as &lt;img&gt; references at the end of each cache description,</li>
            <li><b>ox:all</b> - all images will be included (including spoilers)
                as Garmin's &lt;ox:image&gt; references.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Note: When using "descrefs:" mode, remember to set <b>ns_ground</b> to <b>true</b>.
        The default value is "descrefs:nonspoilers" for compatibilty reasons, but for
        most applications "descrefs:thumblinks" will be the better choice.</p>
        <p>Note: When using "ox:" mode, remember to set <b>ns_ox</b> to <b>true</b>. You must also
        include JPEG files along the GPX for this to work properly - see
        services/caches/formatters/garmin for more information.</p>
        <p>In the future, more generic ways of including images in GPX files may emerge.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='attrs' default='desc:text'>
        <p>This argument controls whether cache attributes are included and how they are included.
        Pipe-separated list consisting of any set of the following values:</p>

        <ul>
            <li><b>desc:text</b> - attributes will be listed (in plain-text) within
            the cache description (<b>ns_ground</b> has to be <b>true</b>),</li>
            <li><b>ox:tags</b> - attributes will be listed as Garmin's <i>ox:tag</i>
            elements (<b>ns_ox</b> has to be <b>true</b>),</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>gc:attrs</b> - attributes will be listed as Groundspeak's
                <i>groundspeak:attribute</i> elements (<b>ns_ground</b> has to be <b>true</b>),
                compatible with Geocaching.com (see the list
                <a href='http://www.geocaching.com/about/icons.aspx'>here</a>).</p>
                <p>Note that most Opencaching attributes don't have Geocaching.com counterparts.
                Such attributes cannot be included as gc:attrs and will be ignored.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>%OKAPI:infotag:ocde-specific% <b>gc_ocde:attrs</b> - attributes will be
                listed as Groundspeak's <i>groundspeak:attribute</i> elements (<b>ns_ground</b>
                has to be <b>true</b>). Opencaching attributes which have no Geocaching.com
                counterparts will be included according to an Opencaching.DE convention, using
                "makeshift IDs" which may change in the future.</p>

                <p>This alternative is supported only by some OC sites (the ones originating
                from the OCDE branch). Other sites will handle <b>gc_ocde:attrs</b> in the same
                way as <b>gc:attrs</b>.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>

        <p>If you don't want any attributes to be included, you must set the <b>attrs</b>
        parameter to <b>none</b>. Using an empty string won't work this way - it will
        trigger the default (<b>desc:text</b>) to be selected, for backward-compatibility.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='protection_areas' default='desc:auto'>
        <p>This argument controls whether protection area information is included and how
        it is included.</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>desc:text</b> - if the cache (probably) is located within one or more
            protection areas, e.g. a nature reserve, a list of the protection areas will
            be included in the cache description.</li>
            <li><b>desc:auto</b> - protection area information may be included in the
            cache description, depending on the installation.</li>
            <li><b>none</b> - no protection area information will be included in the
            GPX data.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Note that information on protection areas may be incomplete or outdated
        or completely missing on some installations.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='trackables' default='none'>
        <p>This argument controls whether information on trackables is included and how it is included.
        One of the following values:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>none</b> - no trackables-data will be included,</li>
            <li><b>desc:list</b> - trackables will be listed (in plain-text) within the cache description,</li>
            <li><b>desc:count</b> - total number of trackables will be included (in plain-text) within the cache description.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Note: When using "desc:" mode, remember to set <b>ns_ground</b> to <b>true</b>.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='recommendations' default='none'>
        <p>This argument controls whether information on recommendations is included and how it is included.
        One of the following values:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>none</b> - no recommendations-info will be included,</li>
            <li><b>desc:count</b> - number of recommendations (and founds) will be included
                (in plain-text) within the cache description.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Note: When using "desc:" mode, remember to set <b>ns_ground</b> to <b>true</b>.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='my_notes' default='none'>
        <p>Allows you to include personal user's notes on each cache. This parameter
        takes either <b>none</b> (default value), or pipe separeted list of the
        following values:</p>

        <ul>
            <li><b>desc:text</b> - include personal notes as part of the cache
            description.</li>

            <li>
                <p><b>gc:personal_note</b> - include personal notes as
                &lt;groundspeak:personal_note&gt; element (under
                &lt;groundspeak:cache&gt; element).</p>

                <p><b>Warning:</b> This element is not a part of
                <i>http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0/1</i> groundspeak schema, but it
                is a <i>http://www.groundspeak.com/cache/1/0/2</i> schema element. Using
                this option will generate formally invalid XML file.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>Note: You need to use Level 3 Authentication in order to set it to anything else than "none".</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='latest_logs' default='false'>
        <p>Boolean. If <b>true</b> then response will include a couple of
        latest log entries for this cache (see also the <b>lpc</b> argument).</p>
        <p>You <b>must</b> set <b>ns_ground</b> argument to <b>true</b> if you want to use this.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='lpc' default='10'>
        Log-entries per cache - the number of log entries included in each returned cache.
        This should be an integer or a special "all" value. Please note, that the <b>ns_ground</b>
        and <b>latest_logs</b> arguments must be set to <b>true</b> in order for the logs to be included.
    </opt>
    <opt name='alt_wpts' default='false'>
        <p>Boolean. If <b>true</b> then we will include additional (alternate) waypoints in the response.
        These are all places associated with the cache.</p>
        <p>Combine this with <b>ns_gsak</b> if you want the result to include additional references between
        waypoints and their geocaches. Please note that not many applications are currently able to
        properly understand GSAK metadata.</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='mark_found' default='false'>
        <p>Boolean. If <b>true</b> then all caches which are already found, will be marked appropriately
        (i.e. with an "found cache" symbol).</p>
        <p>This field requires you to use the <b>user_uuid</b> parameter (or Level 3 Authentication).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name="user_uuid">
        <p>User'd ID. Required to mark found caches using <b>Level 1</b> Authentication.</p>
        <p>If you use <b>Level 3</b> Authentication, you shouldn't use this parameter. Or, to be exact:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>user_uuid</b> will be extracted from the Access Token you use. You don't have to provide it.</li>
            <li>If you provide <b>user_uuid</b>, then it HAS TO match your Access Token. If it doesn't, OKAPI
            will respond with HTTP 400 error.</li>
        </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name="location_source" default='default-coords'>
        <p>If you supply a value, then it must be prefixed with <i>alt_wpt:</i>,
        and should match one of alternate waypoint types documented in the
        <a href="%OKAPI:methodretref:services/caches/geocache#alt_wpts%">alt_wpts</a>
        field returned by <a href="%OKAPI:methodref:services/caches/geocache%">services/caches/geocache</a>
        method. If the type doesn't match, it will be ignored.</p>

        <p>By default, the <b>lat</b> and <b>lon</b> attributes of the <b>&lt;wpt&gt;</b> element
        will return the default coordinates of the cache, as supplied by the owner of the cache.
        This option allows you to replace these coordinates with other set of coordinates, loaded
        from the <b>alt_wpts</b> field mentioned above.</p>

        <p>This may have some advantages in some scenarios. For example, if your user
        is driving a car, he might be more interested in the coordinates of the
        nearest suitable parking spot than in the coordinates of the geocache itself.
        If you set <b>location_source</b> to <b>alt_wpt:parking</b> then you'll be
        pre-fetching parking locations (if provided) without the need of loading all
        other <b>alternate waypoints</b> in your requests.</p>

        <p>Other use case: setting this to <b>alt_wpt:user-coords</b> allows
        personalized results in some OC installations.</p>

        <ul>
            <li>If the type provided doesn't match any alternate waypoints, the default
            coordinates of the geocache will be used.</li>

            <li>
                <p>If the type matches exactly one alternate waypoint, then:</p>

                <ul>
                    <li>The <b>lat</b> and <b>lon</b> attributes of the "primary"
                    <b>&lt;wpt&gt;</b> element will be replaced with the location of
                    the matched alternate waypoint,</li>

                    <li>The name of the geocache will be prefixed with the value suppiled in
                    <b><a href="%OKAPI:methodargref:#location_change_prefix%">location_change_prefix</a></b>
                    parameter,</li>

                    <li>The desription of the waypoint will be included in the
                    header of the cache description,</li>

                    <li>The matched alternate waypoint will be removed from the list
                    of alternate waypoins (in order to avoid duplicate locations),</li>

                    <li>Extra alternate waypoint will be created, with the original
                    location of the geocache.</li>
                </ul>
            </li>

            <li>If the type provided matches multiple alternate waypoints, then
            the first one will be chosen.</li>
        </ul>

    </opt>
    <opt name="location_change_prefix" default="#">
        <p>Prefix to be added to the geocache name, in case its location has been changed due to
        the <b><a href="%OKAPI:methodargref:#location_source%">location_source</a></b> parameter
        matching any of the alternate waypoints.</p>
    </opt>
    <returns>
        <p>GPX file. All invalid cache codes will be skipped without any notice!</p>
    </returns>
</xml>