<xml>
    <brief>Edit an existing log entry image</brief>
    <issue-id>396</issue-id>
    <desc>
        <p>This method allows you to change properties of an existing log entry
        image. If you need to change the image itself, then you'll need to
        delete it and re-add it.</p>

        <p>At least one of the three parameters <b>caption</b>,
        <b>is_spoiler</b> and <b>position</b> must be supplied.</p>
    </desc>
    <req name='image_uuid'>
        <p>ID of the log entry image to be edited. The user of your Access
        Token must be the author of the associated log entry.</p>
    </req>
    <opt name='caption'>
        <p>Plain-text string, a new caption for the image.</p>

        <p>Please note that providing an empty value indicates that your user
        would like to remove the caption, which will often not be allowed
        (then <b>success</b> will be <b>false</b>).</p>
    </opt>
    <opt name='is_spoiler'>
        <p>One of the following:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <b>true</b> - marks the image as spoiler, which means that
                it contains hints for finding the geocache.
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>false</b> - marks the image as non-spoiler.
            </li>
         </ul>
    </opt>
    <opt name='position'>
        <p>If given, it indicates the wanted position of this image on the log
        entry's list of images (do not supply this parameter if you do not want
        to change the order). This parameter takes the same 0-based value as
        described in the <b>add</b> method.</p>

        <p>Some Opencaching installations do not allow the order of log images
        to be changed. Such installations will ignore this parameter (you can
        check the <b>position</b> field in the response to verify if the order
        was actually changed).</p>
    </opt>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of the following structure:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>success</b> - <b>true</b>, if the image was edited successfully,</li>
            <li>
                <b>message</b> - plain-text string, a message for the user,
                which acknowledges success or describes an error (usually you
                want to display this only when <b>success</b> is <b>false</b>),
            </li>
            <li>
                <p><b>position</b>:</p>

                <ul>
                    <li>If you have supplied the <b>position</b> parameter, then this field
                    will contain a 0-based position of the image on the log entry's list
                    of images - the position which was actually saved (it may differ from
                    the position you have requested).</li>

                    <li>If you have not supplied the <b>position</b> parameter, it will
                    contain <b>null</b>.</li>

                    <li>In case of an error, it will also contain <b>null</b>.</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </returns>
</xml>