<xml>
    <brief>Retrieve information on a single user</brief>
    <issue-id>26</issue-id>
    <desc>
        Retrieve information on a single user. This method might be also used
        to retrieve data of the user in who's name the Access Token have been
        issued. To do this, include the Access Token in your request, and <b>don't</b>
        include the user_uuid argument.
    </desc>
    <req name='fields'>
        <p>Pipe-separated list of field names which you are interested with.
        Selected fields will be included in the response. See below for the
        list of available fields.</p>
    </req>
    <opt name='user_uuid'>
        <p>ID of the user.</p>
        <p>This parameter is optional only when you sign your
        request with an Access Token (Level 3 Authentication). Otherwise,
        it is <b>required</b>.</p>
    </opt>
    <common-format-params/>
    <returns>
        <p>A dictionary of fields you have selected. Currently available fields:</p>

        <ul>
            <li><b>uuid</b> - ID of the user,</li>
            <li><b>username</b> - username (login) of the user,</li>
            <li><b>profile_url</b> - URL of the user's Opencaching profile page,</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>is_admin</b> - boolean; true is user has admin privileges.</p>
                <p>This value can be accessed only with <b>Level 3</b> Authentication
                and only for the user of your Access Token. For all other reads, is_admin
                will equal <b>null</b>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>internal_id</b> - internal ID of the user (<b>DO NOT</b> use this!
                use the <b>uuid</b> as the user identifier),
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>date_registered</b> - date (ISO 8601, no time) indicating when the user
                has registered his Opencaching account,
            </li>
            <li><b>caches_found</b> - number of "Found it" and "Attended" log entries,</li>
            <li><b>caches_notfound</b> - number of "Didn't find it" log entries,</li>
            <li><b>caches_hidden</b> - number of caches owned,</li>
            <li><b>rcmds_given</b> - number of recommendations given.</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>home_location</b> - home location of the user in the "lat|lon" format
                (lat and lon are in full degrees with a dot as a decimal point);
                <b>null</b> if no home location is given in the user's Opencaching profile.</p>
                <p>This value can be accessed only with <b>Level 3</b> Authentication
                and only for the user of your Access Token. For all other reads,
                home_location will equal <b>null</b>.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>

        <p>If given user does not exist, the method will respond with an HTTP 400 error.</p>
    </returns>
</xml>